Capture
Wow! I never thought we'd be meeting again like this, Peruru!
Me neither! As soon as I heard the news, I flew right over.
Yeah, I am pretty fast after all.
And Crest also asked me to bring Deep Bite over ASAP.
Thank you, Peruru.
Where's Anna, by the way? Did she go home?
Ah, she went to comfort the mayor.
My approval rating...!
- My approval rating...!
- I-it's okay! It'll go back up again in no time!
Given how chaotic things were at the landfill, I guess it's only natural.
Looks like being daughter of the mayor bears its own heavy burden.
Anyway, what did you want to talk about with Deep Bite?
Well, I summoned Deep Bite because of the cavity he once had.
His cavity?!
I remember Uncle Edo replaced it with a new tooth!
What, are your teeth acting up again? Want me to take a look?
Nah, it's not that, Edo.
When I heard the news about the Wild Cardbots and the virus, Deep Bite's cavity immediately came to mind. Sebastian?
Sir!
Deep Bite went berserk because of this cavity.
Is that...
And Gigantrex, who was bitten by Deep Bite, also began to malfunction. Do you remember?
Yeah. It was a real mess. What about it?
I compared Gigantrex's thought processor circuit data with Deep Bite's decayed tooth, and found the real cause. It was the Beast Virus!
What??
What do you mean by that?
Does that mean you were a Wild Cardbot all along?
So that's why he looks kind of scary!
Guys! No prejudice, please!
Deep Bite has long suffered a lot of emotional pain because of his appearance!
Hahahaha! It's okay. I got over it!
Proud of ya!
But you seem much different than a typical Wild Cardbot. Your Weapon Card is normal, for example...
Viruses, as we understand them, cannot reproduce on their own.
That's why they need to infiltrate a host cell and rewrite its genetic information in order to replicate themselves.
The Beast Virus follows the same process.
However, we've discovered that when a Metal Cardbot is infected, their genetic information is completely rewritten.
This causes them to become aggressive and violent, and their appearance may also change depending on the virus's concentration.
Uh... okay! I understood 100%!
Ah, ah! Their appearance changes! L-like Blue Cop! Who also went through some changes!
Are you sure you understood all that?
Does that mean Deep Bite had already been infected by the Beast Virus? Even before he got a cavity?
That may very well be the case.
Although, I don't know how he managed to come to his senses after being infected.
Unfortunately... I don't have any memory of when I was first infected.
At the very least, his cavity may have been caused by a small amount of the Beast Virus that manifested very late.
So, what are you trying to say?
Are you saying that the bots running rampant through this city aren't pure Wild Cardbots,
but merely Metal Cardbots infected with the virus?
No. He means it's not one of those terrifying viruses where you're guaranteed to die once you get infected. And I'm living proof of that!
And... getting vaccinated can prevent infection.
What?!
Mega Ambler! Let's work together to develop a vaccine for the Beast Virus!
Sigh...
As a doctor, that's an offer I can't refuse.
I'll leave the rest up to you.
Okay! Do your best, guys!
Now then, the next thing we have to do is find the tank kitty and the pony with a spear.
And we also have to find the kid who has a Metal Breath.
Soleil, was it?
She has two companions with her called Blaion and Phantom Hornet.
They were both tough opponents.
Not to mention, they also have the Beast Virus! What if they bite us and we get infected?
I told you to stop watching zombie movies.
Anyway, you guys be careful out there until the vaccine is developed.
Okay. I'll go back to the fire station for now!
Right. I need to get back to the police station as well.
Blue Cop! Take Back!
Huh? Wait!
Jun, I have to get back to work too.
Your wound isn't healed yet. Take a break for now.
Ah... Alright.
Blue Cop is always working himself too hard.
It's important to take breaks, too.
Looks like I'll have to request time off, then.
Ugh. Man, I'm starving. I had too much fun firing my cannon nonstop.
I wonder if there's any good places to eat around here...
Hm? Sniff sniff... this smell!
That... That's gotta be delicious!
Gotta keep my hunger on a leash until I get there!
Welcome!
Hey.
Hello, officer!
Hi. The usual, please.
Yes sir! Coming right up.
Jun, Why haven't I seen your friend around lately?
Ah, well...
Did something happen, Inspector?
A coworker told me they've been bored lately because they haven't seen you around. Did something happen?
It's nothing serious, sir. I'm just getting some maintenance done.
If you say so.
Here you go. One coffee and three 'Luecop's Donuts!
Thank you. Ah. Actually I heard the story about the Wild Cardbots.
How??
Don't worry. We Mowtown police are on the Metal Cardbot's side!
Wait a second...
Was it you, Anna?!
I couldn't help it! It was so hard trying to comfort my dad!
He sees right through everything, so lying won't work on him, so I...!
Don't be too hard on her, Jun. You know there's a heavy burden on Anna's shoulders. Isn't that right?
That's right! Bleeehh~!
Ahahaha... it'll be alright. There's no point in hiding the truth now.
All right, then. I'm going to head back now.
Already?
I just popped in for a quick visit. I also have a lot of things to do, you know.
Gotta take care of the big guys from the Sea of Stars.
By the way, Jun, thanks for the spear.
Hehehe... I kept it nice and safe at my house just for you.
Well then, take good care of Deep Bite. And make sure you do a good job helping with the vaccine research.
Alright, alright.
Cielo, send my regards to everyone.
Will do. Don't worry about it.
Ugh, such a shame to see you go so soon. Share those with everyone, okay?
B-be careful on the way out!
Haha... Thank you for the food! Cielo, I need you to be my eyes!
Okay. Keep going straight!
Yawn... Welcome...
One Dexdex Honey Dip and one Buffy Cream donut, please.
Uh... is that Soleil?
Why are you here?!
For here or to go?
To go, please.
Sure thing, right away. When did you make friends with such a cute girl?
M-Mom!
Do you have any idea how long we've been looking for you?!
I know. That's why I have been hiding.
Grrr... A friend told me that a person doesn't run and hide unless they know they did something wrong!
Here you go.
Thank you.
Wait!
We won't let you go so easily!
Right!
We only came here for donuts... What should we do, Blaion?
Look.
(Breaking news! A major fire has broken out at the Cassias Oil Refinery, located in the northwestern part of Mowtown!)
The oil refinery is engulfed in thick black smoke and flames. Firefighters are working hard to put out the fire, but the flames are proving difficult to control.
Uh-Wait a minute. Uh... that's a Metal Cardbot! We have a visual of a Metal Cardbot with two axes!
That's...!
...Tigun!
(Fire authorities dispatched Phoenix Fire, a Metal Cardbot firefighter, on an emergency call, and...)
- (Fire authorities dispatched Phoenix Fire, a Metal Cardbot firefighter, on an emergency call, and...)
- Ah!
Soleil!
Jun! Let's go!
Yeah!
We should go too!
Theo and Anna, you two stay here and eat more donuts!
Take care of my son out there, Bluey.
Leave it to me, ma'am.
Is everyone okay?
All thanks to you!
Alright! We got ahead of Blaion! We're here first!
This isn't a race, Jun.
Oh, it's Phoenix Fire!
How's it going?
Jun! Blue Cop! The tank bot stole some oil from here and now he's causing a ruckus!
Looks like he's no ordinary glutton.
Jun, what should we do?
We're going in. We have a pro firefighter with us. There's nothing to be afraid of.
Except I'm really afraid! If you underestimate fire, you'll be in for a rude awakening!
Sorry. I'll get serious.
Why don't you let me sweep everything away with my water vortex?
We should save that for later, we can't use that move too often. Let's stick to the plan.
Alrighty!
Where's Tigun?
He's inside, but...
Leave this to us. You go on ahead!
Yes, sir! Follow me!
Heh heh...
The oil here tastes light and mild and real good. Hahaha!
So let's drink some more! Hahahaha!
Stop right there!
Going on a rampage in a dangerous place like this... don't you value your life at all?!
Grr... What? Oil doesn't taste as good without a little thrill!
When we're hungry, we eat! And then we get wild and more wild!
That's the very instinct of my kind... the Wild Cardbots!
If he fires that cannon in a place like this...!
Blue Cop!
On it!
Since we have to live alongside the people who have taken us in...
we can't let you run wild as you please, Tigun!
If that's your instinct, then you follow that!
One more!
Deep Bite! Bite deep!
Phoenix Fire! Set Up!
Burning Hammer!
Heh! You can't hurt me with that toy hammer-
BRUGUBRRRRRRR!
Stay still!
Your turn now! Deep Bite! Set Up!
Let me cool that head of yours, kitty cat!
We have backup?
I think that'll do it if he's that waterlogged, Jun.
Right! Blue Cop, let's finish this!
Yes!
You little...! I'm not here for a squirt gun fight!
What the...?
Heh heh... Blue Cop is skilled in handling electricity.
You know what happens if you get hit by his attack when you're soaking wet, right?
I dunno.
Seriously?
Alpha Bolt...
...Cannon!
Hahahaha! How'd ya like our teamwork?
Alright!
Huh?
Phantom Hornet!
Wild Cardbot!
Change...
Huh? Soleil!
Don't you go stealing our prey!
Phantom Hornet. Set Up.
Bzzzt!
Deep Bite! Set Up!
Veno Spear.
Deep Bite!
Soleil! Why are you doing this?!
It's my mother's wish.
Blaion. Set Up.
Fire Roar Blaze.
Fire Roar...
Blaze!
Change Up.
Deep Bite. Sealed.
I'm going to take your friend with me today.
Bzzt. I don't see Tigun.
Darn. Did he get away? I can't believe he still had the strength to move after that. He's resilient.
He must be overflowing with energy since he drank his fill of oil.
Give us back our comrade Deep Bite!
I'm just following the will of my benefactors!
Let's go now, Blaion.
Got it.
Omega Heat Flame!
Jun! Are you alright?!
Deep Bite...!